<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ovieh Mosley</title>
    <link>https://ovieh.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ovieh Mosley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 09:40:33 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ovieh.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week Two, Part 2</title>
      <link>https://ovieh.github.io/post/week2-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 09:40:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ovieh.github.io/post/week2-2/</guid>
      <description>I submitted my homework. I am not thrilled with my work. I spent many hours trying hacking away at the Bootstrap-Portfolio trying to format it to spec. My biggest isssue is that the breakpoints in our spec are not the same as the breakpoints that Bootstrap 4 uses. The easiest way to have fixed this would have been to customized my own downloaded version of Bootstrap by using Sass, which is something that seemed overly complicated at the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week Two</title>
      <link>https://ovieh.github.io/post/week-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 17:30:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ovieh.github.io/post/week-two/</guid>
      <description>This past week was spent learning the wonders of Responsive CSS. We spent a small amount of time learning media queries, which is fine sense it’s a fairly simple concept. It just involves more hacking around, just with considerations for specific screen sizes. The first part of our homework was to refactor our week one Portfolio Site utilizing media queries. That in itself did not take too much time. The second part of the homework is to refactor the original site using Bootstrap 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week One</title>
      <link>https://ovieh.github.io/post/week-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 20:45:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ovieh.github.io/post/week-one/</guid>
      <description>I am really excited to start a new chapter in my life and puruse something that I am passionate about. It has been a real treat to face challenges and overcome them. Over the next 23 weeks I will transform myself into a Full Stack Developer.
First Weeks Homework My first project was to recrate a Personal Portfolio site from spec. It was a real drag getting all the content to align, utilizing floats and then clearing the floats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio</title>
      <link>https://ovieh.github.io/page/portfolio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 16:11:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ovieh.github.io/page/portfolio/</guid>
      <description> This is dummy text </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://ovieh.github.io/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2017 23:05:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ovieh.github.io/page/about/</guid>
      <description>I am Full Stack Developer located in the Borough of Kings, Brooklyn, New York. I am an avid brewer, photographer and martial artist.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>